PRAVEEN SUDHAKARAN NAIR

Mobile No: +971 563068466 (UAE) Email: Praveen_772@yahoo.co.in Current Location: Abudhabi, UAE.



OBJECTIVE

Seeking for a Server and Network Administrative position in your esteemed organisation where I can implement my professional IT experiences and ideas which will definitely strengthen and expands the company's mission and vision.

IT SUPPORT ENGINEER

Continuing for just over 10 years in IT industry which includes IT support for a small scale business organisation currently in UAE and also for the Internet Technical Support in an ISP in India during my young ages. A proven team player which leads to achieve award winnings, a fast learning, dedicated towards my assignments followed with accuracy and adaptability towards altering and diverse environments.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Operating Systems : Windows 2012 Server R2, Windows Client OS, Linux.

Data Base & Networking : ADOMS(DBMS), SOFTCODE(DBMS), CMTS

(Secure CRT), Mettle wire Server (User Access Server).

• Programming & Testing : Win runner, QTP, Test Director, Load Runner, Java,

Languages Eclipse SDK for Java & Android Developments.

WORK EXPERIENCE

(1) Princess Ruby, Abudhabi, UAE System & Network Support

May 2017 to Till now

- Configuring and maintaining Active Directory, DHCP, DNS, WDS on Server 2012 R2.
- Provides installation including Server OS and other software's needed for daily requirements with respect to our work.
- Maintenance regarding Backup and software updates to be performed on fixed intervals.

(2) Asianet Satellite Communications Ltd. India

April 2013 - April 2017

http://asianetbroadband.in/

Officer Customer Support

- Provide level 3 support for Broadband issues received through email and reply back after thoroughly verifying the configurations on Cisco Broadband Routers based on customer tickets. Finally conforming with customer before closing the tickets.
- Live monitoring, escalating and providing solutions related to Bandwidth issues during peak hours on the entire network links including both Coaxial modem & Fibre Connectivity's.
- Providing on-site support for Primary (Fibre) customers during emergency.

- Co-ordinating with other RF network teams for the customer complaint resolutions and ensure proper escalations if needed like material upgradations.
- Supporting my teammates on their work after my assignment, making sure to reduce the quantity of complaints to the lowest level.
- Provides technical trainings to Beginners by polishing them to our level within a short time span.

(3) Asianet Satellite Communications Ltd. India

November 2008 – March 2013

http://asianetbroadband.in/

Supervisor Customer Support

- Provide level 2 support for Broadband issues receiving through voice and also Walk-in customers by thoroughly verifying the configurations on Cisco Broadband Routers based on customer tickets.
- Analysing and performing network configurations on customer end routers for connectivity issues like IP related issues, Wi-Fi Authentication issues, CCTV Port forwarding issues.
- Provide solutions to Usage issues and also to Login Authentication problems faced by customers by resetting the password after verifying the customer.
- Live monitoring, escalating and providing solutions related to Bandwidth issues during peak hours on the entire network links including both Coaxial modem & Fibre Connectivity's.
- Providing on-site support to customers during emergency conditions like manpower shortage.
- Co-ordinating with other RF & Operation Centre teams for the customer complaint resolutions and ensure proper escalations if needed for material upgradations.

(4) Society for IT Development (SITD), India **Software Testing Trainer**

November 2007 to October 2008.

- Delivering training programs to participants in a classroom environment for both theory and practical sessions and guide them with manual notes.
- Responsible for handling technical queries and respond dynamically.
- Responsible for evaluating student's performance weekly and also for the main exams conducting by the Department Head.

(5) Sun Micro Systems, India Junior Hardware Engineer

January 2007 to October 2007

- Responsible for New PC Hardware Assembling based on the requirement of the customer either financially or performance wise and deliver to customer location.
- Provides support for Hardware and Software issues including OS, based on the maintenance contract with customers.
- Maintenance / Replacement support for faulty hardware at customer location.

Praveen Sudhakaran Nair Mob: +971 563068466

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

 Bachelor of Technology in INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY, Kerala University, Kerala, India. Period from 2002 to 2006.
(WES, Toronto, Canada Approved)

CERTIFICATIONS & TRAININGS ACQUIRED

• IELTS : Listening – 6, Reading – 5.5, Writing – 6, Speaking – 6.5

CCNA Certification : CSCO11213585

MCSE Certification: 14815297 (2012 Server R2)

Android Training : Software Development on Android from ACEWARE Technologies.
NOC Training : Training about Current Network Architecture from Asianet Network

Operation Centre.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Awarded for the Best Employee for the "Support, Effort & Hard work" in 2010.
- Awarded for the Best Performer for "Certificate of Excellence" in 2011.

Praveen Sudhakaran Nair Mob: +971 563068466